Yeah, but welcome to our first encounter gathering of the year.
So excited to be with you all.
If you haven't met yet, my name is Josh.
If you come on Sundays, I talked a little bit,
but I wanted to more formally introduce myself.
My name is Josh. I'm a pastor with Harvest here at the U of M campus in Ann Arbor.
I am one of the pastors. I primarily oversee our college ministry.
I do a bunch of other stuff, but I primarily oversee our college ministry,
And so it's always an awesome season for us to be back in the fall.
I do want to give a disclaimer.
Usually I don't do that.
But the guy who was supposed to do that today got sick.
And so if you know Christopher, please text him and say, we're praying for you.
Hope you get better. Hope you feel better.
But yeah, usually I don't do both.
And so it's not a one-man show.
But yeah, I am so glad to be with you all.
If I don't know, if this is your first time here or this is your first year on campus
and you're checking things out, we're so glad that you're here. Just to introduce my family.
I don't know if they have, yeah, there you go. That is my family. You can, I don't want, I feel
bad saying this. You can ignore the guy on the left. Not because he's not important. He's my
brother Joe, but he lives in California, and so you're very rarely going to see him. But that is
my family. My wife Erica, we got married in 2021, right after COVID vaccinations came out,
if you remember a long, long time ago. But she was a student here. We got to know each other as she
was working for the church as I was a pastor here. I've been here in Ann Arbor since 2015,
and so I've been here. This is the longest I've ever lived in one place, and so I guess I am
officially an Ann Arborite. Although my heart and my stomach belongs to Chicago and the Chicago
suburbs. Anyone from the Chicago suburbs? Yeah, all one of us. Cool. Italian beef and Polish
sausages and deep dish pizza.
All right. But, yeah,
that is my family. My wife Erica and my daughter
Stephanie. She is 10
months and I think a week
today. I'm very sad that I'm
not home with her, but I'm very privileged
to be with you all. I would love to
get you to get to meet
and introduce myself more personally
to some of you. I love meeting with people
all over
campus and just, you know,
in the day-to-day lives and, yeah,
just to share. Maybe it's a good meal or coffee or something and then just to get to know one
another. And so I'd love to get to know you if you want to ever say hi or if you ever want to
meet. Even if you don't want to meet me, if you just really want to meet Stephanie, she is,
I will argue and I will fight. She is the cutest baby that we have here in our church. And I can
say that because there's only one other parent here. Is that right? There's only one other parent
here? Yeah, and I'm pretty sure I can take him in a fight. No, I'm kidding. I'm kidding. St. Cat,
i love you uh he has two and so i don't know how he's awake right now but uh it is it is devastating
but uh i have been here since 2015 joined our pastoral staff in 2017 i've been primarily focused
on our campus ministry uh and i've loved being a part of this church i've loved being a part of
our campus ministry uh we have been around uh for a while as a church we've been around for about 30
years uh and we love this campus we love the students we love people getting to uh come to
the University of Michigan for the first time or other campuses and schools in the area.
We spend a lot of time praying for you all, especially if you're new, especially if it's
your first year, freshmen or chancellors.
We spend a lot of time over the summer praying for you, saying, God, we hope that you meet
them as they come to campus.
We hope that you meet them as they get to hopefully be involved in our church or our
life group ministry somehow.
And our heart for you is just like we sang this evening, that you would get to meet and
encounter, huh, encounter God and his love for you. Would you turn to the person next to you and
say, I hope you meet God and his love? And that for me is my life story, right? I grew up in the
church, right? I grew up around religion and church and faith kind of things for a long time, but
right around the age of like 12, 13, man, there was such a powerful moment when I encountered God's
love in such a drastic, personal, and intangible way that my life has never been the same ever
sins. And I certainly hope that that is true for you. As you enter into college, however long you're
here in Ann Arbor, most people do not stay longer than four, five, six, ten years. Most people at
some point leave Ann Arbor, but as long as you're here, I do pray that you get to meet him, encounter
his love, get to know him. But as we go into tonight's session, we are going to go through a
few weeks of, especially as we're starting off a year, asking and exploring some big questions that
you may be coming into college with. Now, for some of us, we're new to college. We're new freshmen,
transfer students, whatever. You're new. You have a lot of big questions. You have a lot of things
you're excited to explore or whatever else. Some of us, we may need to think back a bit.
I need to think back a bit to my first year of college. I just turned 39 years old. You have no
idea how sad I am that it is my last year before 40. But it's been a while. But if you go back to
your freshman year, what you were looking forward to, maybe some things that you were
excited to try and experience, but also, at least in my experience, there were some questions
that I had, some big questions.
As I got into college, as I was stepping away from my family, my family was in New Jersey
at the time, I went to school in Chicago, I had a lot of big questions like, hey, where
am I going to be, who am I going to belong to, who am I?
Not only career-wise, but is there some personal identity questions?
Who am I? Who was I made to be? Why am I here?
A lot of big, gigantic questions, and we want to explore some of those over the next few weeks.
We don't have time to exhaustively go into it and come out the other side and say,
I have all the answers to everything, like the big questions of life, you know, and everything.
Don't have time for that, but at least to touch on, to explore, and maybe to answer,
does God, does Jesus, does the gospel have anything to offer me when it comes to some of these big questions?
And today, the big question that we want to ask is about belonging.
Can I find a place to belong?
And so just to kind of intro or segue our way into it, can I ask you to turn to the person next to you?
If there's an odd number around you, you know, that's okay.
But can I ask you, just in pairs or threes, was there a time when you felt the loneliest?
Right?
Now, this is a tough question for some of us.
And so if some of us just want to be lighthearted and just answer kind of, you know, I went to,
I visited MSU and I felt lonely because everyone hates, you know, maize and blue.
You know, if you want to answer it like that.
I had that experience.
I mistakenly showed up to a Michigan football game.
I went to Northwestern in a purple shirt.
That was not only the loneliest that I've ever felt, that was also the most fearful I
ever felt in my life as I went into the big house surrounded by maize and blue and people
yelling things at me. But I do want to ask you, maybe you got just in pairs of threes,
was there a time that you felt, you know, significantly lonely? Maybe not the lonely,
but significantly lonely. What was it? What was the situation around it? And did you ever get
through it? Yeah. And so can you do that just for a few minutes? It doesn't have to be too deep.
Maybe about three or four minutes in pairs of threes. When did you feel the loneliness? So go
it, share it, and I'll call us back together in a few. I'm imagining that for most of us,
we can at least empathize with that sensation of loneliness, of having, maybe there's actually
people around you, but this deep sense of, not whether there's people around me, not whether
there's crowds, but this deep sense of belonging. Is there somewhere where I can belong? And for us
as a church, for us as a campus
ministry, for us as Christ followers, we do believe
that there is something that
the gospel offers.
The good news is Jesus offers us.
And it's also an invitation
for us to help build this.
I do want to give this disclaimer. I'm going to be
talking a lot about our church and about
specifically life groups for this year.
If you're new, can I encourage you with all my
heart, go explore what else is on campus.
If you are exploring faith,
exploring Jesus, exploring church communities,
there's a lot of churches and
and fellowship groups, and all of that.
They're doing some wonderful, wonderful things across campus.
Please take some time to check it out throughout the year.
But wherever you end up, I hope that you can maybe live out
some of the things that we're going to look at in the passages today.
And so, yeah, I was, yeah, it's fine.
I was going to say something, but I'm not going to.
My lonely, should I share my loneliness?
I don't know.
Yeah, my freshman year.
I moved into a dorm, kind of similar to that fifth wheel vein.
I moved into a dorm room with my roommate, who was dating the girl that I liked.
And so I wasn't fifth wheel, I was third wheel, but still.
I moved from New Jersey to Chicago for school, and all three of us happened to go to the
same school, and so we all went.
And so partially, I'm like, in my dorm room, I'm like, this guy's either never in the room,
or, like, you know, I'm always third wheeling or whatever, just isolation and loneliness.
But at some point, because I lived in Chicago, I moved away, and then I came back for school,
and I was super excited to be back in Chicago, to be back with my friends.
I took a few months just to be with them.
They were all going to church together, so I went there and, you know, was hanging out there, all that stuff.
In the middle of the year, there was something that happened that made me,
I just couldn't go back to that church anymore, right?
These were the friends I had grown up with.
like I was like young and like elementary, junior high, summer high school, I got to know.
And then at some point, I just, I couldn't go anymore. I was isolated. I didn't have
transportation. And it was just really not a good situation for me to be there. And so halfway
through the year, when all of my doormates had already gotten to know each other, build bonds,
build relationships, then you're an engineer, I'm an engineer, yay, and all that stuff. Like I
entered the middle of the year saying, I thought I had my friends. I thought I had the community of
people that i belong to and then halfway through the year that i that was just taken from me and
then i looked around in my dorm room like i like i know all their names but none of them want anything
to do with me like they weren't trying to be mean it's just the time for building relationships
had passed i had no connections with any of them and i'm just like i don't know what i'm doing here
for all of that i do ask us to think not again you know just are there people around other people
we can hang out with, but a deep sense of
is there somewhere where I can belong?
And if we're exploring
the faith, if we are Christ followers, is there something
that Jesus himself offers us?
We're going to be in two passages today. I'm going to preach
fairly short. I'm going to ask us just to
kind of think about this idea
of belonging. No matter where we
are in our steps of faith, in our journeys
of faith, if we consider ourselves
Christian or not, regardless
we're glad you're here, but
exploring this idea and getting this real strong
sense of, God, do I belong here?
hopefully getting a sense of that. So Luke chapter 5, that'll be our first passage. If you have a
Bible or phone, you can turn there. If not, all the verses will be on the screen. You can just read it
on the screen behind me. But Luke chapter 5, verses 27 through 32, this is an instance in Jesus' life
when he interacts with this one person named Levi. And we'll read it and explore it together
today. Luke chapter 5, verses 27 through 32. It says this,
after this he being jesus after this he went out and saw a tax collector named levi sitting at the
tax booth and he said to him follow me and leaving everything he rose and followed him
and levi made him a great feast in his house and there was a large company of tax collectors and
others reclining at table with them and the pharisees and their scribes grumbled at his
disciples saying why do you eat and drink with tax collectors and sinners and jesus answered them
those who are well have no need
of a physician but those who are sick
have not come to call the righteous
but sinners to repentance
Amen. Can I pray
for us real quick before we dig into
this passage here tonight
let's pray together
God I thank you for the gift of
your word not only just for us to
study and study some text on a page
or screen but it reveals
something about your character, your heart
what you care about
And I pray that as we dig into this passage tonight and the others, that you would speak to us.
What you are speaking personally to us, how you are drawing every one of us personally in.
God, I pray that that would be clear for each one of us as we go through tonight.
And so speak to us, help me speak clearly as we go through tonight.
I pray this in Jesus' name. Amen.
So we talk about the sense of belonging.
You know, that word isn't necessarily listed or written out in this passage that we've just read.
But I do think that you see this picture of Jesus bringing a gathering of people together.
And the point I want to draw out is this, is that Jesus builds a community of radical grace.
That Jesus builds a community of radical grace.
If you look at verse 27, we're immediately introduced to this guy Levi.
He's a tax collector.
His old identity is really summed up in these two ideas of being a tax collector and sinner.
It describes a group of these kind of people later.
But tax collector and sinner.
Tax collectors, that might not sound super bad,
but if you're familiar with this time, with this period, what's going on,
Levi is Jewish, at least ethnically Jewish,
maybe not super religious in his faith,
but he is ethnically Jewish,
and he has been, maybe he volunteered, maybe he's been consigned,
I'm not entirely sure,
but Levi somehow makes his way to becoming a tax collector,
and for him, the taxes he's collecting is not just for the Jewish people,
The taxes he's collecting is actually for the Roman government.
The Roman government has taken over the Jewish people.
They've kind of taken over and conquered them as a people group.
And so for a Levite to be a tax collector meant, one, that he was betraying his own people by collecting taxes from them.
And two, most likely, it doesn't specifically say this, but most likely, if you are a tax collector,
you collect whatever you want from the people that you're collecting taxes from.
and you send a certain amount to the government,
but you can keep the rest for yourself.
And so if you're not collecting anything above and beyond
what you're sending to the government,
you're not making a living.
You're starving, you're going day to day, whatever.
And so you have to overcharge the people in order to survive.
And so most likely Levi is not only collecting taxes
for the oppressive government,
but he's also overcharging, extorting his people
so that he can make a living.
And so for the Jewish people, they're like,
hey, you're not only a tax collector,
you're a sinner, you're a terrible, evil person,
you're a terrible, evil human being,
and generally they'd just be shunned in society back then.
It is to this Levi who has been ostracized,
who has been overlooked, who has been looked down upon,
it is this Levi who is known as a tax collector and sinner
that Jesus shows up in his life.
And what do we see?
We don't see Jesus condemning him.
We don't see Jesus calling him out for his tax practices and all of that.
what Jesus does in verses 27 and 28, he invites him into relationship. There's an invitation to
relationship. Look at verse 27 at the end of it. Jesus said to Levi, follow me. And leaving
everything, Levi rose and followed him, being Jesus. There's this invitation to relationship
that's immediately shown, both in Levi saying, okay, Jesus, you say follow, I'm going to follow.
And not only that, there is this presentation there at this feast. There is this invitation
that Levi makes to other people,
but it's in the context of Jesus has invited me
into relationship, and so I want to invite other people
as I have this new relationship with this guy.
This invitation with Jesus was so powerful
that he leaves everything,
gathers the people that he knows,
and says, this is the guy I'm spending time with now.
And so what do you see in verse 29?
You see a community gathering.
It's not just a meal, right?
You can eat just bread and like,
hey, you're hungry, I have some bread for you, and that's it. This is not just a meal. This is a
feast, right? I don't know if some of you went into the dorms and be like, feast, or you're just
like, no. Actually, I don't know how the dorm foods are. Anyone think the dorm foods are really,
really cool? Cool, good stuff? No, some? Some hands, actually, yeah. It's been a long time since
I've eaten in a dorm. If you want to invite me to eat into a dorm, I will gladly accept that
invitation. Just saying. But this is a feast. This is not a meal to sustain. This is not the
bare minimum. This is something that's saying, hey, I want to spend time with you all as much
as I'm spending time with this guy. I want to invite you to do this. This is a time of happiness,
of joy. No one goes to a feast sad. I mean, you can't go to a feast. Feasts are supposed to be
happy, right? Feasts are supposed to be this joyful event, this community event where you're together
and feeling this joy together. And that's what Levi wanted to share. But in the next few verses,
you see the shift.
Not only is there this feast
and celebration and moment of joy
there are these people who I'm
putting into my own words
they call out what's going
on. They call out Jesus and his followers
and say, why are you guys hanging out with
these people?
I can't put enough
stank on these. Why are you hanging out
with these people?
These Pharisees, they had
seen, they knew,
they were the ones
probably leading in the charge and saying, hey, these tax collectors, they're betraying
us. They're denying their own heritage. They're denying their people groups.
They are against us. We shouldn't be hanging out. We shouldn't be spending time with
dirty, dirty people like them. And so there's this question, why are you guys
hanging out? Why do they belong with you?
But we see Jesus in the midst of all of this.
That he answers. And if I could
summarize or rephrase
what he's saying. Jesus
builds a community. Jesus builds a gathering
starting with Levi that's based on
Jesus' own identity
and purpose.
He's not come to say, I'm a good person
gathering more good people.
He's not saying, I'm a moral person, come to gather
more moral people. He says,
I'm a doctor. I'm a physician.
These people are sick.
I've come to call them and be with them.
I've come for the unhealthy. I've come for the sick.
I've come for the people who don't think they're righteous
and I want to build my community.
I want to build my gathering with them.
And so as we see Levi,
as we see this moment where Jesus invites him
and this gathering that forms,
I want to ask us, again,
that question that we began with,
where do I belong?
We're in school.
We have things going on.
There's things we could try to belong to.
There's some things that you are hoping to belong to.
Maybe student orgs.
Maybe social clubs.
Maybe some of us in the B school and trying to get into that one student group that, you know,
would look really, really good on your resume.
There's frats and sororities that you can apply to and try and get hazed for and try to enter into.
There's dorms, maybe community that's built.
Maybe there's something about maybe a shared hobby or interest, a sport that you play or arts
and things that you're interested in pursuing that you want to say,
hey, I want to find like-minded people and spend all my time with them.
Maybe it's for future success.
maybe it's just that, hey, I really value this thing in my life. I want to spend more time with
people who value it too. I love anime. I want to watch anime with other people. That's not me.
Sorry. That's not, if you all love anime, good for you. I don't. That's just, that's just me. I'm not
judging you or anything like that. I like professional wrestling. You can judge me for
that all you want. But all of that to say, where do you belong? Or maybe even the follow question of
Where do you want to belong?
If we dig deeper, there might be even some semblance of,
I want to find belonging in something that's very personal to me,
my identity, my ethnicity, my socioeconomic group,
my political allegiance.
Where do I belong?
And I think the wonderful thing that we see in this passage
is that Jesus is building a community
where a lot of that stuff doesn't matter.
I mean, it matters because it's part of who you are.
It's shaped you to be the person that you are today.
But at the same time, it doesn't matter in terms of,
well, you can belong to Jesus.
Jesus still invites us.
Jesus still invites, no matter what shape we are.
If Jesus can invite someone as messed up
and as lowly and despised as Levi,
then there's no reason why any of us
can't hear the same call of Jesus Christ to say,
come follow me, come be with me,
come be in relationship.
with me that for us is why we gather not only spaces like this but in smaller settings and
community settings and specifically life group settings and i thought it'd be helpful if it
wasn't just me talking and so i wanted to ask someone to share their experience of how they
found belonging how they found a sense of belonging specifically through life groups and so i'm going
to invite jessica to come up and share her testimony tonight can you give her a hand as she
she comes up and she'll share with us. My name is Jess, and today I'd like to share a little bit
about my testimony with Life Group and belonging. So I remember some of my very first times coming
to Life Group a whole 12 months ago. Holy cow, time flies. And I remember like those very first
Life Groups, it was like, ooh, icebreakers, like ooh, Bible study, ooh, wow, refreshments, like
and for those of you who don't know me super super fun fact about me I have an extremely severe
life-threatening dairy and raw egg allergy and I remember those some of those very first life
groups people actually took the time to check the life group directory and prepare refreshments that
I could eat which was really shocking to me because I was used to sitting in a corner at
birthday parties, watching other people eat the birthday cake that I couldn't eat. But at Life
Group, they had like dairy-free tiramisu for me. That was incredible. And like, so right off the
cuff, I knew that something was different about the kind of love and care that I experienced in
Life Group, which now, a whole year later, I can confidently say is an overflow of God's love.
and as life group went on, the semester went on, it got harder unfortunately and sometimes I would
come into life group feeling a bit down or beat up with school and other things like swaying down
on my mind. Shout out a few of my life group leaders and members who would be able to look
at me in the eye and immediately know that something was up and I remember all I had to do
sometimes is just like take one a little bit intense scary eye contact look at me and ask
if I was okay or what was wrong and literally I would just like break down crying and like spilling
out my guts to them which was pretty surprising to me because a lot of my friends who may have
known me for longer who came to college with me from the same high school wouldn't notice things
like that as fast and it really shocked me how much these people who at that point were still
strangers for the most part cared and noticed enough to see what was going on with me beneath
the surface and I think that's a huge part of belonging is the idea of feeling seen and known
and loved for who you are and not just how necessarily how you present yourself and as a
whole. Taking the time to sacrificially serve and love one another is such a true testament to God's
love, which I was so blessed to see and experience, whether that be driving each other around. I was
the passenger princess, one of them. Opening up homes and apartments for devos, making refreshments,
attending one another's like concerts and events. Just so many examples of showing up for people in
ways that in today's like increasingly independent isolated like individualistic society may seem
like a lot to ask in other places was really just like the norm and the culture here and what really
set life group apart for me is that like this connection to others this commitment to get to
know one another is not based on anything that you have to do or you have to be no like external
marker of your identity. But in Life Group, I've been so blessed to see people so like completely
and wholeheartedly invest in other people for that reason in and of itself, to know and love
these people so genuinely, just to love people like Christ does. And I also grew up in a really
demographically homogenous small town in the Midwest called Midland, Michigan. Shout out
Midland Michigan where oftentimes I was like the only person who looked like me in classrooms or
other spaces and it ingrained in me a really deep sense of otherness and I always felt like I had
something to prove to others something I had to do in order to earn my spot at the table or justify
why I was there and that was something that was so different with life group and I really had to
unlearn because life group made it so easy to feel belonging early on and I had to relearn that
being loved did not require anything to earn belonging and like not a need to be perfect or
an expectation of never making mistakes but really just being there for each other when it's easy and
when it's hard, showing up where it matters. And that is just such a genuine privilege and a
reflection of Christ's love that there isn't something to be earned or boxes to be checked
before you can experience love and belonging in the kingdom of Jesus Christ, our Lord and Savior.
Thank you. God's grace, the radical grace and community that's built from it can look like
dairy-free tiramisu.
Look at the person next to you and say,
Jesus can show up in desserts.
Hopefully you don't take that literally.
Like, oh my gosh, I see Jesus. No.
But that's where God's grace can be shown.
Hey, people are considering me. They're seeing me.
And in grace and love,
you might be new and they might still try and show up
for you. It might be in
showing up for events, for gatherings,
for different things that are important to you
that are outside of the weekly gathering and they show up
for you anyways. Whatever it is,
the sacrifice, the investment,
I hope that if you are new
or even if you're returning,
that all of us can experience,
wait, this is somewhere where I can belong,
where I don't need to perform,
where I don't need to live up to some standard,
where I can be
because of the grace and love of Jesus Christ.
That is our hope.
That is our aim.
And that's why we're preaching this tonight
as we start off a year.
We hope that you do find that sense of belonging
in our life groups
and in our church community.
No matter what you've done in the past, no matter what guilt or shame that you feel,
no matter how you view yourself, there's a Jesus who offers this radical grace,
and we want our communities to show that radical grace as well.
That grace, that generosity, that favor, that I didn't do anything to deserve this,
yet this good thing is happening to me and for me.
I don't deserve anything good. I don't deserve people's kindness.
I don't deserve Jesus' love, and yet Jesus shows up.
but he invites Levi into a relationship
and for us to experience that in our life of gatherings.
I pray that we would find that,
that foundation, that central direction,
a Jesus who shows a grace so radical and powerful
that it can change your life.
Levi went from tax collector and sinner
to being primarily known as one of Jesus' followers.
In the rest of the Bible,
he is often referred to by his other name, Matthew.
He's one of Jesus' disciples, his followers,
and he did a lot of leading in the early church.
Jesus' love and grace can change his life
and he can change yours
but Jesus paradoxically
sometimes
as much as he's come
to build this community
to build a church built on his radical grace
paradoxically
he doesn't necessarily do it by snapping his fingers
and saying it's just magically going to come together
for better or for worse
in our opinion, in my opinion
but in Jesus' perfect wisdom and insight
and knowledge and all of those things.
Jesus invites us, invites you and me to say,
if I'm building a community, if I'm building a gathering,
if I'm building a church that bears my name,
that is built on this radical grace,
he is inviting you and me to help build that together with him.
And that's what we want to explore.
If you want to turn to 1 Peter 1, we'll end here.
He doesn't instantly form it.
He doesn't instantly make all of the churches around the world
just perfect in love and grace and unity and all of that.
He builds it and gives the foundation for it for sure,
but he encourages and calls us to say,
hey, would you join me as I'm trying to build my gathering,
my people on this foundation of radical grace?
1 Peter 1, verse 22 to the first verse of chapter 2.
1 Peter 1, 22 to 2, chapter 1.
It says this.
Having purified your souls by your obedience to the truth
for sincere brotherly love,
love one another
earnestly from a pure heart.
Since you have been born again,
not of perishable seed,
but of imperishable,
through the living and abiding word of God.
For all flesh is like grass
and all its glory like the flower of grass.
The grass withers
and the flower falls,
but the word of the Lord remains forever.
And this word is the good news
that was preached to you.
If I could summarize what this passage
is trying to exhort us and challenge us to understand and grasp.
We find a place to belong as we commit to communities that show radical grace.
And I don't know if this seems paradoxical to you.
I don't know if this seems contrary to you to what we had just talked about.
If radical grace is about, you don't have to do anything, you don't have to perform anything,
you can experience God's grace and love in your life,
I mean, we believe that, yes, and amen.
But for us to be that community, for us to experience that community,
for us to belong to that community,
we need to understand that this gift is not a gift like you can just give a package to someone
and they receive a gift.
This gift is given to us in the form of relationships,
and relationships require commitment.
If I show up at home after tonight and go home to Erica,
Stephanie is probably going to be sleeping. Just home to Erica.
If I go to her,
I'm going to be like, hey,
I love you. You know that, right?
She's like, yeah. I love you with all my
heart, soul, mind, all that stuff. Yeah, of course
I know. But I found someone
else too. I'm wondering if
they're going to text her about this illustration in just a moment.
If I go home and say, hey, I found somebody
else, and so as much as I love you, I'm going to
love them too.
What do you think her reaction would be?
See, I see some people in the back who think they know her,
and they say, she's going to slap me.
That would be an appropriate response, saying,
what do you think you're doing?
You are not committed to it.
You see this ring.
I'm the only one who has this ring from you.
You better not.
Honestly, if you know Erica, she'd just roll her eyes and be like,
yeah, sure, whatever.
And then, you know, let's go to it.
Like, she knows me too well, and she has sarcasm running through her veins.
And so she will just lovingly just roll her eyes and say,
shut up go to sleep you know all that kind of stuff there is a commitment that's expected as
much as this radical grace is the foundation as much as it is what we want to experience for us to
experience relationships communities of radical grace this requires some sense of commitment not
as a prerequisite to earn that is not what i'm trying to say at all but to deepen our experience
of that love of that grace of that community it does involve commitment i don't know if you know
the phrase you get out what you put in for us as we consider communities and radical grace it does
require a sense of commitment and that's i think what this passage is trying to teach us in verse
22 there's a sense of radical grace includes effortful intentional love i don't know if you've
thought about this idea how can love be commanded right how can love be commanded uh if i commanded
you to jump, you know, you could do it.
You're not going to do it because you're like, why? But you could do it. You could command someone and they
can choose to obey or not obey. You know, that's fine. But that's something that you
can do because that's something in their power to, you know, it's just an action. You're like, hey, jump.
You know, whatever. If I tell you, stop
feeling tired. Just by show of hands, how many of us are tired
tonight? How many of you got like less than five hours of sleep
last night wow a few less than four okay somewhere in the four to five range is that roughly yeah uh
i am so sorry that is that's tough uh and your first week of school too oh that uh if i if you
get like you know it's finals week you're getting like no you got like half hour of sleep a night
you know something like that and i tell you the day after like no just stop feeling tired can you
do it? No. Right? Some of you will try other things like coffee or whatever tries to get you
waking up or whatever else. But there's some things that you're like, I can't, you can't command me to
do this because I can't. I just can't. You tell me to change, you tell me to do something, I just
can't. How do you command love? And if you command love, doesn't it stop being authentic and genuine?
If you command it out of someone, isn't it something that is forced out of you?
You're compelled to do it, not that it's coming from a genuine and authentic place.
I want to offer two thoughts.
One is that there's a difference of the feeling of being in love versus the actual act of loving.
C.S. Lewis writes this,
Being in love is a good thing, but it's not the best thing.
in fact whatever people say the state of being in love usually does not last but of course ceasing
to be in love need not mean ceasing to love love in the second sense love as distinct from being in
love is not merely a feeling it is a deep unity it is a deep unity maintained by the will
and deliberately strengthened by habit,
reinforced by the grace
which both partners ask and receive from God,
they can have this love for each other
even at those moments when they do not like each other,
as you love yourself even when you do not like yourself.
I mean, primarily he is talking about marriage here,
but I think the principle of love still stands.
Yes, you can stop being in love.
That can't necessarily be forced or commanded,
and you can't change that on a whim necessarily.
But at the same time, the command to love.
Love your husband, love your wife, love your spouse,
love your parents, love your siblings,
love your children, love your neighbors.
This call to love, as it is this deep unity,
can be commanded.
And it doesn't make it fake.
It means that there's something deeper
that is holding you together,
even when you don't like the other person,
for you to say, no, I'm going to love this person genuinely from the heart, even if I don't feel it.
Think about God.
He is so unlike us.
Even if you don't believe in God, the concept of a God is so foreign.
It should be so distinct and foreign to be some kind of entity out there that is so much bigger,
who is present across all the universe, who can see all things and understand all things with just a glimpse.
what would he have in common with people like you and me
who are limited by our own experiences
and what we can see and sense
this God who is different
who is separate from us
what we see in scripture is also that
this God is a God who has been rejected by his people
rejected by
God I don't want to be in relation
I don't want you to be my God
I don't want to be your person
we don't want to be your people
we reject you as our overseeing God
and yet God still loves us
how he sends Jesus
for us.
It takes effort for Jesus
to come down in the form of a human being,
but it is effortful, intentional
love that he goes,
he lives a human life,
he dies on a cross for you and I
so that we would understand
just how much he loves us.
For us, the communities that we want
to build, the communities that we want to
find and experience, the life group
communities that we want to have
this coming year are life groups
of radical grace
where it includes effortful, intentional love.
See, effortless love,
I mean, you can find it.
You can go out exploring.
You can find the people that you click with.
Again, for me, pro wrestling fans,
I've got to ask again.
Anyone?
Anyone want to watch Raw on Monday?
No?
It's on Netflix now.
You can find it.
It might be hard to find it.
It might be really hard to find it,
but you can find it if you want.
These are the people that I connect with.
These are the people that I click with.
These are the people that I can spend hours and hours and hours
talking about the bloodline and Roman Reigns and John Cena
and his retirement tour and how bad it was
and how much he should have done all of this.
You can find your people.
You can find that click.
But is that the love that Jesus shows?
I grew up, I grew up in a very distinct ethnic church.
I grew up, I mean, my parents are from Korea.
I'm a Korean American.
My stomach will always belong to Korea.
There is a part of that there that is always true.
But there is, I grew up in that church.
And so for me, the sense of belonging was not only about faith.
It was also about, oh, these are my people because they can speak the second language.
Well, I can't really speak it that well.
Please don't talk to me in Korean.
I'm going to really struggle with that.
But, you know, these are people who look like me.
They talk like me.
They eat the same foods that I do.
It is effortless for me to step into those spaces and be like, I have missed my people.
I have missed the lunches they serve after Sunday service.
I have missed the ways that they show affection and care for people.
It would be so effortless for me to step into that space.
But it's effortful for me to say, as different as you are from me, I still want to be in loving relationship and community with you.
Different cultures, different backgrounds, different interests, different hobbies, different personality types.
How many of you consider yourselves introverted?
Cool, you are my people.
I know I'm loud, but I am super introverted.
I'm the loudest, maybe the loudest introvert you might ever meet.
Because I will yell, not at you.
I just have to give you this disclaimer if you're new.
If I yell, I'm not yelling at you, usually.
Look at the person next to me and say he's not yelling at you.
I'm just yelling in front of you, if that's okay.
I yell and then I go home and I'm like,
I just need to sit on the couch for like
an hour, just doing nothing.
Maybe holding Stephanie at most.
That's how I recover my time.
Introverts
and extroverts. Spending time
together. Some of you introverts
are like, please no.
Some of you extroverts are like, please no.
You might want
that group that has fun like you do.
That wants to spend
the time like you want to spend the time.
But for us to be part of these groups and say,
I'm giving up some of my preferences
I'm giving up even some of my
ideals about. It'd be so much easier
for me to say I'm finding people like
me, who look like me, who talk the language
that I do, who come from a similar
socioeconomic background that I am.
It is
an effortful, intentional love to say
I'm willing to give up my preferences
to find a deeper unity and
love in Jesus Christ.
Or even loving people who might not
be easy to love.
Again, if you're new, please
explore. Explore the fellowships and churches.
There's so much good stuff that God is doing
across Ann Arbor and across this campus.
But for us, the communities
that we want to build, the communities that are marked
by radical grace that we want to build,
we want them to be marked by effortful, intentional
love, saying, hey, I want to
love you, even if I don't necessarily feel it.
Not to make it fake,
but to say we want to find a deeper and truer
love in Jesus Christ.
Secondly, radical grace involves
costly commitment, verses 23 to 25.
there's this whole metaphor of a seed
and being imperishable and the word of God
and grass and all that stuff
overall there's this understanding that
there's this enduring thing
this infinite
forever lasting thing
that is the seed, that is the word of God
in verse 25 Peter directly connects that word of God
to the gospel, to the good news
the
imperishable seed
that God has given you life
through is the good news about
Jesus Christ
Jesus Christ, who died for us, who sacrificed himself to demonstrate that love for us,
that is the costly commitment that he not only does for us so that we can experience radical grace,
but that he models for us to say, this is also the costly commitment that I want my people to show to each other.
This gospel, this God's love is not a temporary thing.
It is not something that can be taken from you at a moment's notice.
It is something that will last forever because that is our God and that is how his love lasts.
And so a love that is not temporary, a love that is not fleeting,
a love that will not just vanish because God just doesn't feel it anymore.
He is committed to this and it costs him something,
and that is the radical grace that he calls us to show one another as well.
For us, we view our life group communities as something to commit to.
Not to say like you're signing a contract and like you have to show up to X amount of dates.
That's not it at all.
It is a relational thing.
And it's saying, hey, I'm joining this group.
And sure, I may have weeks where I can't come
and I can't make the weekly meeting or whatever else.
But still, these are my people.
These are my relationships.
These are my community for this year.
These are the people that I want to be connected to
in love and grace because of Jesus.
What prevents that commitment?
I mean, there's superficial stuff.
Sickness can keep you from people.
If some of you are prone to being sick,
I get sick every other day
please don't talk to me
because I don't want to get you sick
I mean that might be a thing
hopefully your life groups care about you enough
to bring you care packages
and medicine and soups
and all that
but honestly most of it tends to be
fear
I know I'm going to date myself
and show myself as old
there's an old phrase that I can't get over
that for some of us
what's going to challenge our commitment
to these communities to find this grace
is the fear of missing out.
FOMO is no longer a thing, right?
You guys don't say that on a day-to-day basis.
Sinka, do you say that ever?
Is it a thing?
You guys still say FOMO?
Yes, I'm not too old, yes.
All right, FOMO, fear of missing out.
What causes someone to say,
I don't want to commit to you,
I think I have better options.
i have a better option for fun i have a better option for my future success i have a better
option for my career and i'm not saying that these things are not important or valuable
but when we are driven by that fear when we're driven by a fear of saying i want i am worried
that there's something better out there for me then we look at our relationships and say you're
not a relationship you're a commodity you're something for me to consume you're something
that if you don't meet up to my standards if you don't meet up to my desires then what good are you
I'm out. Jesus didn't do that with us. It cost him something to show us love. It cost him something
to build that relationship with us. And for us to say we want our life groups to show Christ's love
means that we are going to commit to one another. Again, yes, there are seasons where we are more
active, less active. I mean, those things happen. But for us to relationally say, this is the people
that God has called me to commit to so that I can both experience and show God's radical grace.
And finally, the last principle coming from chapter 2, verse 1.
Radical grace enables us to be open to being hurt.
2-1.
So put away all malice, all deceit, hypocrisy, and envy, and slander.
All slander.
If you look at that list, malice, deceit, lying, hypocrisy,
when you're envious or jealous,
when you start slandering all the people, talking bad about them,
trying to destroy their reputations.
Where does that come from?
Honestly, I look at that list
and I'm thinking, man, the people who do this
are people who have been hurt
and they don't want to be hurt again.
Hurt people, slander others.
Hurt people, lie.
And I'm going to get what I want.
I'm going to lie to get what I want
because I've been hurt and disappointed before.
Radical grace.
If we truly understand Christ's radical grace
and how he wants us to live that on the community.
It means that, man, we have to be vulnerable,
we have to be open,
we have to be willing to say,
I'm going to expose myself to these people
as a sign of commitment to them,
as a sign of grace for them,
and also to be exposed so that I can receive grace.
Because I don't know about you,
there's a couple of situations
where being vulnerable really matter.
If you are in a battle
and you are exposed with no armor,
you are opening yourself up to being hurt for sure.
But at the same time,
I imagine if you're in a hospital and you need to get a surgery, you are exposing yourself.
You're stripped naked.
The team is looking at your body and trying to explore where this pain or this issue is coming from.
You are exposing yourself to be hurt, but you're not experiencing that hurt in the hospital.
You're experiencing people going into your life, going deep and saying,
this is where I want your healing to be found.
Radical grace, if we understand it, it enables us to be open to being hurt.
And yes, we might get hurt.
Vulnerability, there is that risk that runs from there.
But it's saying, if I'm open to being hurt,
hopefully that'll help others find
grace. Maybe as
I'm being vulnerable, people will
also feel like they can be vulnerable and
find the deeper healing that they need to find
in Jesus Christ. Because here's
the truth. Vulnerability, I mean, God knows
everything about you. He knows the worst
things about you.
He's already known that. He's already
loved you. And for us,
as we want to explore that in community, we want
to say, if God loves us at our worst,
we want to be free to show that to others
to have people
speak love and grace back into our lives
and to be able to share that with others as well
I hope for every single one of us
that we experience
Jesus' radical grace that he
shows
but I also hope that we understand
that he calls us to join him
saying the radical grace that I'm showing
to you, I want this
to be lived out in your life groups or whatever
communities that you commit to this
year. That's why the one thing
for today is this, is to commit to biblical
community, to find and
to demonstrate radical
grace. Whether it's here or
elsewhere, I hope that happens for us.
It's pretty easy to find
a Bible study if you want to.
Hey, we're just here to study a passage.
It's pretty easy to find
a friend group if you have the right hobbies
or if you have the right interest or the personality
or ethnic background or something like that.
But to find
communities where we can
experience this radical grace, it does
take a bit of commitment for us.
But it's possible
because Jesus has already
shown it to us as well.